Welcome to Sherlock 1895!
Sherlock: The Abominable Bride is a crime, drama,
mystery film directed by Douglas Mackinnon.
Sherlock Holmes and Dr.
Watson find themselves in 1890s London in this holiday special.
Sherlock Holmes, played by Benedict Cumberbatch.
Dr. John Watson, played by Martin Freeman.
Mrs. Hudson, played by Una Stubbs.
DI Lestrade, played by Rupert Graves.
Mycroft Holmes, played by Mark Gatiss.
Professor Moriarty, played by Andrew Scott.
"The Abominable Bride" is a special episode of the
British television programme Sherlock.
The episode was broadcast on BBC One, PBS and Channel One on 1 January 2016.
It depicts the characters of the show in an alternative timeline: the Victorian
London setting of the original stories by Arthur Conan Doyle.
The title is based on the quote "Ricoletti of the club foot and his abominable wife" from "The
Adventure of the Musgrave Ritual" (1893), which refers to a case mentioned by Holmes.
The story also draws on elements of original Conan Doyle stories of Holmes such
as "The Five Orange Pips" (1891) and "The Final Problem" (1893).
The episode won the Primetime Emmy Award for Outstanding Television
Movie, the first win of the series in that category.
The film explores themes of bride, police detective, crime
investigation, tv episode, homicide investigation.
The tone is intense and emotional and mind_bending.